“深空之门”拜拜了您哪~哈喽呀LOP-G
Goodbye Deep-Space Gateway, hello LOP-G
是不是奇怪我在抽什么风？
Now just in case you're wondering what I'm going on about
本期视频讲的是国际空间站退役后的下一代空间站
this is the news that the next Space Station the one to replace the ISS
Trumpian “非常川普的”
最近呢它有了更加川普的名字
has had a bit of a Trumpian makeover
不行 这名字太川(S)普(B)了 我决定依然叫它“深空之门”
全程叫“月球轨道平台-门”，简称“LOP-G”，而不是之前的“深空之门”
and will now be called the Lunar Orbital Platform Gateway or LOP-G instead of Deep-Space Gateway
这事我们一会再说
but we'll come back to that a bit later
现在，人类造过最贵的东西是国际空间站
Now the most expensive object ever built was the International Space Station
其花费包括发射组装、维护与来自俄罗斯、欧盟、日本、加拿大的捐赠
which combining launch assembly, maintenance and contributions from Russia, Europe, Japan and Canada
目前一共花了1500亿美元
has so far cost more than $150 Billion
20000天是按人算的，比如三人在上面停留一天，算作三天
按这个价格，假设从2000年到2015年，国际空间站上乘员一共度过20000天的话
Using that price tag if we assume that the ISS has had some 20,000 person days from 2000 to 2015
可以得到价格大约是每人每天花费750万美元
it works out at about $7.5 Million dollars per person per day
美国的上一代空间站——天空实验室，大约是每人每天550万美元
The previous U.S. space station Skylab, was about $5.5 million dollars per person per day
即使是本来就很烧钱的航天工程，1500亿也是个相当大的数字了
Even by the standards of space programs $150 billion is an astronomical sum
相比而言，阿波罗工程总共花费约1090亿美元（换算成2010年的美元）
The entire cost of the Apollo program adjusted for inflation has been estimated at a $109 Billion
2000年提出的去火星的星座计划，预算也只有400亿美元
and the Constellation Mars program which was in 2000 was projected at a mere $40 Billion
而国际空间站的花费还在继续提升
The bill for the ISS will also continue to rise
NASA最近承诺的预算是2024年之前每年投资30亿美元
NASA has recently committed to a future investment of $3 billion per year until at least 2024
但为什么一个空间站项目就给NASA弄到这么多预算
But why has a space station received so much of NASA's budget
而别的那么多牛逼项目不是砍经费就是直接被砍？
where many other ambitious programs suffer cuts and cancellation
想回答这个问题，我们要考虑到历史的进程，来了解下人类第一个近地轨道空间站
To answer this question we have to look back at the history of the first space stations in low-earth orbit
六十年代的时候，美国和苏联都在砸钱造大火箭
In the 1960s both the USA and the USSR invested in designing massive rockets
目的是送很重的东西入轨，进而登月
specialized for lifting super heavy payloads into orbit and onto the moon
土星五号近地轨道运力高达140吨
The Saturn V could carry an unsurpassed 140 tons into low-earth orbit
苏联的N1超级烟花理论上能送95吨
The Soviet N1 rocket was designed to lift 95 tons above the earth
虽然它四次试射都变成了超级烟花
even though it never actually made it past its first four test flights
尽管下一代——能源号——能把一百吨的暴风雪号航天飞机送入近地轨道
Though its successor the Energia which flew the Buran into orbit was able to lift a 100 tons
但当时美国人早就登月了
When it became clear that the Americans would be the first humans to land on the lunar surface
苏联一想，咱还是有大运力火箭的，那换个研究方向吧
the USSR shifted their focus to another thing you can do with a super heavy launch capacity
然后他们就去搞空间站了
This shifting focus began an ambitious program of Space Station development
金刚石计划是苏联的军事侦查太空站计划
这个计划于1971年至1974年发射了一系列太空站
为了掩盖其军事目的，这些太空站利用礼炮计划来掩饰
以上来自维基百科
苏联在1971-1986年间发射了礼炮1-4号空间站，当中还有三个金刚石计划的军用空间站
The Soviets launching four Salyut space stations and three Almaz military stations between 1971 and 1986
美国与之对应，在1973年发射了天空实验室
America answered with the 1973 launch of Skylab
原视频YouTuber口误
天空实验室的发射火箭是魔改的土星五号（去掉三级），而不是土星1B
一个魔改了土星五号后发射的、单体77吨的空间站
a 77 tons station built from a modified upper stage for Saturn 1b (Saturn V)
能容纳三人，最后于1979年坠毁在澳大利亚
which hosted three manned crews before re-entering over Australia in 1979
接着美国转而开发航天飞机
And from that point the U.S. then concentrated on the space shuttle
虽然苏联的礼炮空间站非常小，只有19吨
Although the Soviet Salyut stations were much smaller at less than 19 tons each
但它为之后首个模块化空间站——和平号——打下了基础
they paved the way for Mir, the first modular space station
但当1991年苏联解体后，西方政府担心苏联火箭实验室的人才流失
But when the USSR collapsed in 1991, western governments worried that the brain drain from the Soviet rocket labs
会给流氓政权输送拥有洲际导弹技术的科学家与工程师
could provide rogue states with engineers and scientists to spread ballistic missile technology
为了避免此事，美国政府为失业的俄罗斯工程师找了好多相对和平的活干
To avoid this, the American government searched for ways to keep Russian engineers employed in peaceful space projects
这个和平的活就是把原有的和平2号空间站计划变为建造新的国际空间站
One solution was to repurpose the plan for the Soviet Mir-2 space station To form part of a new International Space Station
苏联工程师说吼哇，然后和平2号的第一个模块就变成了国际空间站的两个核心舱了
This was agreed upon and the first modules from the MIR-2 were adapted to form two of the core modules of the ISS
不过当然，国际空间站也有美国的工程师参与
The ISS also provided continued employment for American engineers
航天飞机前后发射了26次，为其运送组件
and the space shuttle which flew 26 missions to lift the components into orbit
这个大家伙在地球上看都是划过天空的亮点
Visible from all over Earth as a bright dot racing across the night sky
它在人类最动荡的年代，为全球太空项目提供了又好又贵的合作平台
the ISS provided an impressive and expensive collaborative purpose
for the world space programs at a crucial moment at the end of the most violent century of human history
但在投资、开发了几十年后，ISS终究会在不远的将来
But after decades of development and investment the ISS will at some point in the not-too-distant future
退役、然后再次落回地球，结束三十来年的任务
be abandoned to the forces of Earth's atmosphere ending its 30 years or so mission
化为南太平洋上空，人类历史上最昂贵的一幕烟花
as the most expensive firework display in history somewhere over the Pacific Ocean
与此同时，航天产业也迎来了一轮新的动荡
Meanwhile the space industry is going through another period of turbulence
一场新的太空竞赛，这次在国企与私人公司之间展开
a new space race, this time between public and private agencies
在下个十年里，NASA打算再本世纪二十年代建造一个新的空间站
Looking ahead to the next decade, NASA has gone back to the drawing board
to plan a new International Space Station for the 2020s
这个项目貌似也有当前特朗普政府的支持
This project also appears to have the support of the current US presidential administration
你现在是不是在想，我们下一代空间站是不是特别大的环形的
If you are thinking that by now we will have space stations with giant centrifugal rings
能为上面居住、工作的人提供人工重力
creating artificial gravity for the living and working quarters
就像五十年来各种科幻作品中提到的那样？那你就要失望了
like ones that were all the rage in the sci-fi films 50 or so years ago, then you'll be rather disappointed
实际上如果你把深空之门和现在的国际空间站比，你都高兴不到哪去
In fact if you're comparing the LOP-G to the ISS you're going to be disappointed
相比国际空间站的16个模块，深空之门将只有四个模块，比国际空间站小得多
The LOP-G in its current form will be a lot smaller with just four modules compared to the 16 of the ISS
与国际空间站一样，深空之门将来也是私营公司与各大国企之间合作的产物
Like the ISS, the LOP-G will be a collaborative venture between private and public entities
投资将来自NASA、俄罗斯宇航局、欧空局、日本宇宙航空研究开发机构和加拿大宇航局
and will draw upon funding from NASA, Rososmos, ESA, JAXA - Japanese Space Agency and CSA - the Canadian Space Agency
而与国际空间站不同的是，深空之门将来自之前被砍掉的计划
Unlike the ISS, the LOP-G will draw upon designs of previous cancelled projects
第一个模块叫PPE，全称“能源与推进组件”
The first proposed module is the PPE or Power and Propulsion Element
顾名思义，它将提供电能与离子推进的动力
and will provide as the name suggests electrical power plant and an ion thruster propulsion capability
PPE两端有国际标准的对接口，用于对接其余模块
The PPE will feature international docking system standard ports either end for connecting additional modules
还能和俄罗斯下一代载人飞船之类的对接
and ones like the next generation Russian spacecraft
甚至可能在将来，和中国的模块对接
and possibly at some point in the future a Chinese module
做梦吧你
PPE前身是陨石重定向任务中的自动化飞船
The PPE is based on a robotic spacecraft designed as part of the Asteroid Redirect Mission or ARM
这个任务去年被撤资了
That mission which was defunded last year
原定是着陆到地球附近的陨石上
and aimed to land on a near-earth asteroid
抓一把石头，带回地月空间，供宇航员研究
capturing a boulder and returning it to cislunar space for study by astronauts
7.5吨的PPE模块目前定于SLS的第二探索任务(EM2)中与猎户座一同发射
The 7-1/2 ton PPE module is set to launch on the Exploration Mission 2, EM2
时间暂定2022年到2023年间，将是SLS的第二次发射
That will be the second mission for the SLS and the Orion spacecraft in 2022-23
这也将是猎户座成员模块首次载人飞行
This will also be the first manned flight of the Orion crewed module
所以此次任务成功与否极大地取决于新的太空发射系统功能是否符合预期
so mission success will depend a lot upon the new systems functioning as planned
SLS将把猎户座飞船与PPE送入地月转移轨道
The SLS will deliver the Orion and the PPE to a translunar injection orbit
进入地月转移轨道后船箭分离
which will then set the space station off towards a course to the moon
之后PPE上的推进系统会点火，进入预定轨道
Then the PPE's thrusters will fire for the first time to complete the planned orbit
轨道并不是环月轨道
This isn't a lunar orbit
而是同步轨道与月球轨道中间的地月空间
It will be in cislunar space which means an orbit between geostationary Earth orbit and lunar orbit
在这个位置，空间站会同时远离地球引力与月球引力
Here the space station will remain outside of much of the Earth's and the moon's gravity wells
这样以后回地球或者去月球都很容易
allowing efficient access for future missions either to the moon or back to the earth
SLS构型1B火箭地月转移轨道运力39吨
The SLS block 1B rocket can actually lift 39 metric tons into translunar injection orbit
足够一次发射整个深空之门空间站，或者装不下就分两次运
enough to lift all four sections of the proposed LOP-G in one launch or two depending upon volume limitations
但目前的计划是每次发射单独一个模块外加一个猎户座飞船
However the current plan is to launch each module alongside a 23 ton Orion spacecraft
剩余三个模块是居住模块、后勤模块和最后的气闸模块，预计在20年代中期完成
and deliver the habitation module, then the Logistics Module and finally the airlock by the middle of the 2020s
每次任务都会有四名成员在深空之门中驻留21天
On each of these missions a four-person crew will be able to remain at the LOP-G for up to 21 days
这是猎户座最长任务时间的两倍
doubling Orion's maximum mission time
于是问题来了，如果深空之门比国际空间站小得多，那它有啥用？
So if the LOP-G is going to be much smaller than the ISS what will it be used for
一个主要目标是测试将来火星任务的设备
One of the main goals is testing equipment for the upcoming Mars missions
当深空之门四个模块组装完成时
When the LOP-G is fully assembled with its four modules
气闸舱还将供新的深空运输模块停靠
the airlock will double as a berth for construction of the new deep-space transport (DST)
这个大型行星际可复用飞船将载人前往火星
This large interplanetary spacecraft will be a reusable manned craft to take humans on towards Mars
深空之门还将离开地球磁场的保护
The LOP-G will also be outside of the Earth's magnetic field and the protection it gives
直面各种高能粒子、宇宙射线
against charged particles and cosmic rays
于是问题又来了，阿波罗的时候咱们人类不是已经离开过了么？还测试什么？
Now some might say why do we need to redo all the testing when it was done with Apollo
时间最长的阿波罗任务是阿波罗17号，3天月面停留，全程12天
Well the longest Apollo mission was Apollo 17 and it was 12 days long including three days on the moon
相比现在，当时用的还是六十年前的科技
and compared to now it used 60-year old tech
人类从中学到了很多东西，制造技术也飞速发展，但仍需测试
We've learned a lot since then and manufacturing techniques have changed dramatically but it's still needs testing
前往火星的任务长达六个月，回来也一样
Missions to Mars will be six months there and the same coming back
比阿波罗的时间长到不知道哪里去，而且从来没人去过
much longer and in deep space where no human has been before
深空之门给了我们在这类环境中测试的绝佳机会，同时离地球还没那么远
The LOP-G gives us the best opportunity to test the conditions like this but still be relatively close to the earth
它还可以远程控制月球上的设备
It could also be used to remotely operate equipment on the moon
并作为下一代登月计划中前往月球与返回地球的中转站
and be a stopping-off point for the next generation of lunar explorers
as a transit from the earth to the moon and in back again
无论如何，如果深空之门可以演示、验证人类在地球磁场保护之外生存的技术需求
However if the LOP-G can demonstrate and prove the technology needed to survive beyond the Earth's magnetosphere
同时还有像SLS或者私人公司比如太空叉的发射载具得到验证的话
then a proven launch platform such as the SLS or maybe a private company like SpaceX
那它都会打开未来更加长远、更富野心的、探索整个太阳系的计划的大门
it may open the door for a more long-term program of more ambitious missions around the solar system
不过当然啦，在我们迈出下一步载人探索之前，国际政治上的合作也是很重要的
As always, a giant leap forward in political cooperation will be necessary
before we take the next steps towards manned exploration of our planetary neighborhood
所以你觉得我们会在20年代中期把深空之门建成吗
So do you think we'll get the LOP-G up and running by the mid-2020s
还是像之前一些计划中画的饼那样，变成政治的套路？
or will it fall victim to the political flip-flopping that has plagued previous space programs
说的就是你，BFR
SLS一发十亿美元，会不会被将来某个更加便宜、可复用的系统取代？
And will the SLS at a billion dollars a launch be sidelined at some point in the future for a much cheaper reusable system
欢迎在评论区留言讨论
Let me know what you think in the comments
墙裂感谢各位充电的小伙伴对给虫的支持
Now I would also like to take time to thank all of our Patreons for their ongoing
YouTuber的频道叫Curious Droid，欢迎过去资瓷一下
support and you can find out more about that in the link now showing
不要忘了关注一下给虫哦，给虫会经常更新航空航天类的科普视频
And don't forget the curious droid Facebook group and page for suggestions and ideas for upcoming videos
最后感谢观看，记得点赞、投币、收藏、分享一波
So until the next time please subscribe thumbs up and share